[ wind chimes tinkling ]
[ woman singing Spanish lullaby ]
Subtitles by explosiveskull Sync by GoldenBeard
[ woman speaking Spanish ]
[ laughter echoing ]
[ wind blowing ]
[ Diego ] Mama ?
Bartolo ?
Mama ?
- [ water sloshing ] - [ gasping ]
[ Bartolo grunting ]
[ gasping ]
[ screaming ]
Mama , no !
[ Anna ] Sam , come on . We 're late .
Guys , the bus is almost here .
Chris , in case I 'm late for any reason ,
there 's dinner in the fridge .
[ Chris ] Meatloaf . Got it .
Misty !
Sorry , sweetie .
[ Chris ] Mom , where 's my jacket ?
[ Anna ] It 's in the closet upstairs .
Quick , quick , quick .
Lunchbox .
All right . Okay . I got my keys .
And ... No .
No , no , honey , I already packed it .
Here you go . Take your backpack . Let 's go .
Chris ? Let 's go .
- Come on , guys . - Oh , I see it .
[ Anna ] What ? Honey , no , you can 't wear these .
- Okay . - We 're gonna miss the bus .
[ Anna ] Let 's go , let 's go , let 's go . Come on .
Shit !
Language , Mom .
[ man ] Department of Social Services .
[ Mr. Hankins ] Oh , Donna ,
what 's the latest from the Alvarez case ?
[ Donna ] I called several times .
She 's not answering the phone .
I 'm taking patrol over there . Something 's up at that house .
Patricia Alvarez ?
Why ? What 's going on ?
We got a call from the school .
Alvarez boys aren 't going to class again .
Okay , well , why is Donna going over there ?
I transferred some of your cases .
Now , Donna has more energy .
- More energy ? - And more time .
She doesn 't have the outside responsibilities you have .
- She has no kids . - She has support at home .
' Cause her husband isn 't dead .
She was on time every day this week .
All right ? But believe me , we all understand .
Do you ?
Doesn 't really feel like it .
Less time here , more time at home
might not be such a bad thing .
Patricia Alvarez isn 't gonna talk to someone like Donna .
" Someone like Donna " ?
I just mean that she knows me .
I 've been with that family for four years .
I 've seen those kids grow up . Patricia trusts me .
She knows that I 'm a mom , too .
The job is to do what 's best for the kids .
Okay , okay , look . Just keep the case .
Once you get done here , check in with patrol .
- I don 't need patrol . - Take an officer .
That 's not a request .
[ officer ] I 'm sorry .
[ Anna ] You know what , I can handle this myself , okay ?
I 'm sure you can .
[ baby crying in other house ]
[ sighs ]
Hi , Patricia .
How are you ?
Are the boys home ?
- Ma 'am , open the door . - No , that 's okay .
Just give us a second .
Patricia , where are the boys ?
They 're somewhere safe , Anna .
[ Anna ] Oh .
Look , I don 't know what 's going on ,
but I might be your best bet at clearing things up .
So why don 't you let me in
and you can show me that they 're safe , like you said ?
No , he doesn 't even have to come inside .
Okay ? Why don 't you just let me in ?
[ door chain unfastens ]
Uh-uh . Promised her that I 'd go in alone .
Yeah , out of respect for Officer Garcia .
Your husband was a police officer .
You think he 'd let you go in there alone ?
Yeah , I do .
[ sighs ] I 'll be right here .
Thank you .
- [ door chain fastens ] - [ sighs ]
Patricia , what happened in here ?
Where are the boys ?
If you 're drinking again or if you 're having some kinda ...
[ shushing ]
[ breath trembling ]
[ softly ] Listen .
What ?
What do you hear ?
Her crying .
[ mutters in Spanish ]
[ door opens and closes ]
[ gasps softly ]
[ faint thud ]
Carlos ?
Tomas ?
[ gasps ]
Get away from that door , Anna .
- Patricia ... - Get out , Anna .
What do you have inside here ?
- [ speaks Spanish ] - Patricia , please . I just ...
[ in English ] Get out !
Please , just tell me what 's in here .
- Get out ! - [ Anna gasps ]
- [ grunts ] - Stay away from that door !
- [ officer ] Anna ! Anna ! Anna ! - I told you ! Get out !
- [ Anna screams ] - [ officer ] Jesus Christ !
Get off of her ! Now ! [ grunting ]
[ Patricia ] Don 't open the door !
- Calm down ! Stop ! - Just one more night , Anna !
[ officer ] I said calm down !
[ Patricia ] Just one more night !
- Let go of me ! - [ panting ]
You don 't understand !
[ door creaking ]
[ gasps ]
Oh , my God !
[ whispers ] Close the door , please .
[ whispers ] She 'll hurt us .
No , she won 't .
I promise .
[ siren wailing in distance ]
Guys , everything 's all settled .
You 're gonna have warm beds ,
and hot food ,
and a shower .
Okay ?
My gosh !
How did that happen ?
She did it .
Your mother did that to you ?
[ Tomas ] No .
It wasn 't her .
Your mother loves you . You know that , right ?
Whatever 's happening ,
we 're gonna take care of it , okay ?
But for tonight , you guys are safe .
I promise you .
We 're not safe anywhere .
[ cackling ]
[ whimpering ]
Hi !
Sorry I 'm late .
How was school ?
[ Samantha ] Same old , same old .
Hey , Sam .
Hey .
There was meatloaf in the fridge .
Did Chris warm it up for you ?
I don 't know .
[ singsong ] Hello ?
Yeah , he heated it up .
Okay . Where is he ?
He 's playing in Dad 's office .
[ Anna ] Not too much TV , okay ?
[ Chris ] We 've got a 10-15 in Midtown .
Suspect is on the run .
I 'm pursuing on foot .
I think I see something .
There he is .
I 'm on his tail . I see the suspect .
I need backup .
Bam , bam !
I need backup . I 'm taking fire !
Freeze !
Bam , bam , bam ! I got him .
I got the suspect .
Call it in , Coop . We got him .
Mom , I 'm all done !
[ sobs ]
I 'm coming ! [ sniffles ]
Right . Let 's see .
Okay .
Rinsing .
[ gasps loudly ]
[ door thuds in distance ]
[ door creaks ]
- [ footsteps approaching ] - [ keys jangling ]
[ door opens and shuts ]
[ gasps ]
[ woman crying nearby ]
[ whispering ] Tomas . Tomas .
[ electricity buzzing ]
[ yelling ] Tomas .
Tomas .
[ electricity continues buzzing ]
[ whispering ] Tomas , what are you doing ?
Tomas , come back .
[ Tomas gasps ]
[ La Llorona ] Carlos .
[ screaming ]
[ phone ringing ]
[ gasps ]
Hello ?
Anna , it 's Coop .
We just pulled the Alvarez boys out of the river .
I 'm gonna need you to meet me at Fourth and Mission .
Okay , I 'll be right there .
[ police siren wailing ]
Stay in the car . Okay ?
And please don 't wake up your sister .
I 'll be back in a few minutes .
[ faint police radio chatter ]
[ officer ] I 'll keep checking on this one .
This way , ma 'am .
[ officer ] All right .
[ indistinct chatter ]
[ Anna gasps ]
Oh , my God !
I don 't understand . What happened ?
We found them in the river . They were drowned .
When you saw them , how were they ?
They were fine .
They were scared , but they were fine , Coop !
I promised them that they would be safe , Coop .
- I promised them . - Anna , don 't blame yourself .
[ Patricia screaming ]
Mis hijos ! Mis hijos !
[ officer ] Hey ! Hold her .
[ shouting in Spanish ]
[ in English ] It 's your fault !
I tried to stop her !
[ speaking Spanish ]
Who ?
Who did you try to stop ?
La Llorona .
[ siren wailing ]
[ camera flash pops ]
[ camera flash popping ]
[ camera whirring ]
[ woman sobbing ]
[ continues sobbing ]
[ gasps ]
[ softly ] Nino ...
Mijito ...
Mijo ...
[ Chris shuddering ]
[ La Llorona speaking Spanish ]
- [ sizzling ] - [ screaming ]
[ La Llorona ] Nino !
Sam ! Sam , let me in !
- Open the door ! Hurry ! - Chris ? What are you ...
Open !
[ panting heavily ]
[ door alarm beeping ]
[ screaming ]
[ gasping ]
What 's going on ?
Didn 't you see her ?
Who ?
[ panting ]
[ squeaking ]
[ Chris gasps ]
[ Chris grunting ]
[ Samantha ] Chris , what 's going on ?
[ gasping ]
Chris ?
[ winder squeaks ]
[ gasps ]
[ grunts ]
[ straining ]
[ panting ]
[ breathing deeply ]
[ gasping ]
Hey , sorry , guys .
Are you okay ?
Yeah .
Yeah , I 'm fine .
[ sighs ]
I 'm fine .
You okay , honey ?
Yeah . I was just imagining things .
Okay .
Night .
Love you .
[ inaudible ]
[ Father Perez ] He 's a curandero .
The ritual is called smudging .
It 's supposed to rid the body of any negativity
that may have attached itself to it
during times of great stress .
Do you believe it works ?
[ chuckles softly ]
What does it matter what I believe ?
It 's what they believe .
And if they believe in that ,
then surely they believe in this .
Did you know the boys ?
Yeah . I was their case worker .
Can I ask you a question , Father ?
Yes .
Do you know anything about La Llorona ?
[ gasps softly ]
I haven 't heard that name since I was a child .
The Weeping Woman .
She was known for her beauty .
The most beautiful woman in that part of Mexico .
Then one day , a rich and handsome ranchero
rode into her village . [ chuckles ]
She set her sights on him .
The marriage was splendid .
They had two beautiful children whom they treasured .
But then , after a time ,
she discovered him in the arms of a younger woman .
What 'd she do ?
She took from him what was most priceless .
She murdered their children .
In a fit of jealous rage , she drowned them in the river .
After she realized what she had done ,
- she was consumed by guilt . - [ sobbing ]
She threw herself into those same waters .
Then is cursed to roam the earth ,
searching for children to take their place .
Children are told to behave ,
listen to their elders ,
or La Llorona will come and steal them away .
So it 's a folktale ?
To some .
Here .
It has seen me through many dark nights .
May it do the same for you .
Oh , thank you but my husband was the religious one , not me .
You don 't have to be religious
to have faith .
[ thunder rumbles ]
[ thunder rumbling ]
[ sobbing in distance ]
[ sobbing continues ]
[ sobbing stops ]
[ thunder rumbling ]
[ breathing heavily ]
- [ wind blows ] - [ gasps ]
- [ wind gusting ] - [ gasps ]
[ thunder rumbling ]
- [ screaming ] - [ sizzles ]
[ gasping ]
Chris ?
Chris !
Sam ?
[ footsteps running ]
[ Samantha whimpering ]
Sam ?
What 's going on , honey ?
Honey , what happened to your arm ?
I fell .
That 's quite a fall .
Hey .
I know things are a little bit hard right now .
And I know that the world sometimes seems scary .
But I was thinking ,
remember what Daddy used to say ?
About if you were scared and he wasn 't there ?
He 'd tell you to hold onto to Misty
and you squeeze her really tight .
Does it feel any better ?
That feels a little bit better , right ?
What are you looking at ?
[ knock on door ]
Coop 's here .
Come on .
Come on , sweetie .
[ thunder rumbling ]
Rough day , guys ?
Can we go watch TV ?
Sure .
[ sighs heavily ]
[ TV playing ]
Um ...
Cheers ?
It 's been that kinda day , huh ?
- Week . - Month ?
- Year . - [ chuckles ]
I don 't know . They 're hanging in .
I think we need ...
Time .
Yeah .
And the occasional takeout ,
so thank you .
You 're welcome .
Well , if you 're not in the mood
to talk personal problems ,
how about professional ones ?
Oh , no . What ?
It 's about Patricia Alvarez .
We know that she had some involvement
in her sons ' deaths , but she has a solid alibi .
Several parishioners at her church say
they saw her at the time that her kids were taken .
Really ?
You know her story . Just take a look at the file .
Maybe you 'll see something I missed .
I would love to help you
but she does not want to see me .
Well , that 's just it .
She 's angry at you .
And one of the first things
your husband ever taught me is that ...
Angry people love to talk .
[ sighs ]
[ Carlos ] She did it .
[ squeaking ]
[ door thuds ]
[ wind blowing ]
[ door slams open ]
[ hinges creaking ]
- [ door opens ] - [ gasps ]
[ door closes ]
[ door continues opening and closing ]
[ breathing shakily ]
[ wind blowing ]
[ sighs in relief ]
Chris .
What are you doing ?
Hey .
You okay , honey ?
Chris ?
Honey ?
You all right ?
You okay , honey ?
- Chris ? - [ gasps ]
[ Chris panting rapidly ]
[ Anna gasps ]
[ groans ]
Chris ?
Honey . Hey .
Come on .
Hey , wake up .
What happened ?
You were sleepwalking , baby .
Oh , sweetie .
You were just sleepwalking .
It 's okay .
Come on . Come on , baby .
Let 's get you upstairs . Let 's go to sleep .
Come on .
You 're okay .
[ rustling ]
[ switch clicks ]
Is there someone in here ?
Because my husband is a cop
and he 's gonna be home any minute now .
[ door opens , creaking ]
[ screaming ]
Sam ! Chris !
Kids , wake up ! Open the door !
Open the door !
[ panting ]
[ screams ]
What are you doing in my house ?
[ gasping ]
Get out of my house !
- [ screams ] - Mom ?
[ Samantha ] What happened ?
[ continues gasping ]
Nothing . Nothing .
Nothing , honey . Nothing .
I 'm sorry . Come on in , honey .
Go on , go on .
Why don 't you sleep in Mommy 's bed tonight , okay ?
[ breath trembling ]
- [ alarm beeping ] - [ gasps ]
[ Samantha moaning ]
[ Samantha ] Chris , get your foot off of me .
What ?
[ door buzzes ]
Patricia ?
I 'm very sorry about your loss .
I can 't even imagine how you must feel .
How I feel ?
[ scoffs ]
I feel nothing .
Because I have felt the worst .
I am done .
I don 't care what they do to me .
You should be sitting here instead of me .
You killed my boys , not me .
[ speaks Spanish ]
Patricia , you had them locked up .
I had them hidden .
[ speaks Spanish ]
[ in English ] And now she has them !
She has them !
[ whispers ] Mis hijos .
What happened to your arm ?
What happened to you , Patricia ?
La Llorona .
Your children ,
have they heard her crying ?
Have they felt the sting of her tears ?
They will . Soon .
And she will come for them .
You know why ?
Because I told her to .
No , Patricia ...
You know , when my boys died ,
I didn 't pray to God for their salvation .
Instead , I prayed to her .
[ chuckles ]
I prayed ,
and I prayed , and I prayed to her
to give my children back to me
and take yours instead .
[ inhales sharply ]
[ muffled thud ]
[ breathing shakily ]
[ faint thud ]
[ grunts ]
[ Samantha sobbing ]
Sam ?
[ Samantha continues sobbing ]
- [ wind gusting ] - [ grunts ]
[ gasping ]
[ screaming ]
[ panting ]
[ wind blowing ]
[ screaming ]
Chris !
What ?
[ Chris groaning ]
[ gasps ] Chris !
Chris !
- [ Chris inhaling sharply ] - [ indistinct PA announcement ]
- [ doctor ] Ah . - [ Chris exhales ]
Sprained this pretty bad , champ .
[ knocking on door ]
[ Anna ] Cooper , hi .
What ?
The hospital called ?
Yeah .
Welfare check .
[ Donna ] Samantha , how did you get those burns ?
How about you , Chris ?
I told you , I fell .
Is that true ?
Where was your mom ?
Anna , you know you can 't be here .
Oh , come on , Donna . I wouldn 't ...
They 're trying to protect you .
They 're telling you the truth .
I would never hurt my kids .
She 's right .
You can 't be here .
[ Donna sighs ]
You may not believe this , but I hate having to be here .
I promised your dad I 'd watch out for you guys .
So if you ever need anything ,
just call me . Got it ?
We had to release Patricia Alvarez .
Didn 't have enough to charge her .
Maybe she didn 't do it .
What do you mean ?
I don 't know . Never mind .
Anna ,
whatever 's going on here ,
fix it .
Dad , for the first time in my life , I 'm in love .
That 's very serious .
[ Anna ] Hey .
And she loves me , Dad .
Chris ...
Can we talk ?
Honey , I need to know what really happened .
[ water splashing ]
[ Chris ] I saw a woman .
In the house ?
In Samantha 's room .
I thought it was Sam but ...
A woman in a white dress .
She was crying .
She wants us .
She wants us to be hers .
Ow . Mom , that hurts .
Rinsing .
You believe me ?
Yes .
I do .
[ grunting ]
[ gasping heavily ]
[ muffled screaming ]
[ faint thudding ]
Sam ?
Sam ! Sam !
Sam ! Open the door ! Sam !
Sam !
[ grunts ]
[ Samantha coughing ]
[ gasping deeply ]
What happened ? What happened to you ?
Honey .
You okay ? What happened ?
Sam ?
[ whimpering ]
[ Chris ] Mom .
[ stammers ] Mom . Mom !
Mom !
- [ screeching ] - [ screaming ]
- [ sizzling ] - [ screaming ]
[ groans ] Go !
[ Samantha continues screaming ]
Go ! Run !
Go !
Run !
[ whimpers ]
- [ rumbling ] - [ yelling ]
[ door rattling ]
Run !
Go !
- [ whimpers ] - [ rumbling stops ]
[ Anna ] I know it sounds hard to believe .
[ Father Perez ] A few years ago ,
I placed little stock in legends , myths ,
things that go bump in the night .
But then
there was an incident
with a doll .
It opened my mind
to possibilities out of the ordinary .
Can you help us ?
The Church works with people
who specialize in situations like this .
Okay .
But to get to them , we 'd have to go through the archdiocese .
How long does that take ?
At its best , several weeks for a case to be approved .
[ Anna ] No .
There may be another way .
It 's unorthodox , but he 's local .
However , if you choose this route ,
I must obey the laws of the Church ,
and remove myself from this process .
As I said , his methods are unorthodox .
And the Church , well ,
the Church has their ways , and he has his .
It 's why he abandoned the collar years ago .
He used to be a priest .
Yes .
But now , he 's a faith healer .
A shaman who operates
on the fringes of religion and science .
A curandero .
- [ music playing on radio ] - [ door bells jingling ]
Don 't touch anything , okay ?
Hola . Excuse me .
- Um ... - I 've seen you before .
The Alvarez memorial .
Yes ?
Yes . I was her case worker .
Well , if you 've come just to gawk at my shop ,
I have more important things to do .
You know what , I don 't think that
we 're in the right spot . I 'm sorry .
Come on , guys .
Have you seen this before ?
Yes .
What is it ?
The Church can help you .
No , no , no , please . The Church sent us here , to you .
This is Church business .
Please .
[ Rafael ] These are the marks of La Llorona .
You have seen her then ?
[ Anna ] You ever seen her ?
No .
Not directly .
But I have seen what she does .
What do we do ?
We are facing an evil that has no bounds .
But she 's not human . Right ?
No . But she was ,
until her murderous vanity consumed her .
She 's just a dark spirit .
Unholy . Forsaken by God .
Okay , that 's it . I 'm gonna take them to a motel .
Why ?
She 's attached herself to your family , not your house .
If you move , she will follow you .
What are we supposed to do then ?
I don 't think that 's gonna help .
No . Not just this .
At the memorial ,
I saw you speaking with Father Perez .
He said that you used to be a priest .
My journey began in the Church .
Yes .
That was a long time ago .
Take me to your home . We must begin immediately .
We 're done .
I 'm sorry , are you just gonna rub eggs all over everything ?
You think it 's silly , don 't you ?
Pretty much .
Come with me .
This ritual , la limpia ,
is used to detect the presence of evil .
The bloodier the content ,
the greater the evil .
[ chanting in Spanish ]
Oh , that 's a trick . I saw it on Johnny Carson .
Mom .
[ all gasp ]
Ta-da .
Did you see that on Carson ?
No .
[ praying in Spanish ]
Amen .
[ Rafael in English ] We all need to work together .
La Llorona thrives in darkness .
Let 's prepare .
[ muttering prayer ]
That cross was carved from a tree in Mexico .
It blooms with red blossoms
that make it look like it 's on fire .
[ speaks Spanish ]
The fire tree .
[ in English ] They say
the fire trees wept
as La Llorona drowned her children .
As the only witness to her sins ,
they hold a special power over her .
[ blowing ]
In nomine Patris , et Filii , et Spiritus Sancti .
Amen .
What is that ?
[ Rafael ] The tears of La Llorona .
I 've sanctified them .
Why ?
Antivenom .
[ thunder rumbling ]
Is that another ritual ?
Yes . Breakfast for dinner .
That was David 's thing .
Breakfast for dinner . I used to always tease him
it was ' cause cereal was the only thing
he knew how to make .
Tonight , la comida is for comfort ,
after everything that you 've been through ,
and what 's to come .
You don 't seem very confident .
I 'm confident in God .
Father Perez said you turned your back on the Church .
The Church ? Yes .
God ? Never .
- [ electricity crackles ] - [ Anna gasps ]
Get the kids .
[ rattling ]
Watch the flames .
A steady flame tells us
that our protective charms are working .
Is she coming ?
She 's already here .
[ loud thud ]
[ floorboard creaks ]
[ thudding ]
[ all shuddering ]
- [ thudding continues ] - [ floorboard creaking ]
What is she doing ?
She 's searching .
For what ?
Us .
[ La Llorona screeching ]
[ all shuddering ]
[ water dripping ]
[ breathing shakily ]
[ faint whisper ]
[ sizzling ]
[ Anna gasps ]
[ screaming ]
[ children screaming ]
Mom !
[ Samantha ] Mommy ?
[ gasping ]
[ muttering ]
[ rattling ]
[ Samantha ] Rafael ,
help us .
[ both gasping ]
[ thud ]
[ wood creaking ]
[ whispers ] Mis hijos .
[ Chris and Samantha screaming ]
[ Chris ] Mom !
Mom , she 's got me !
[ screaming ]
Mom !
[ Samantha ] Chris !
[ Chris ] Mom !
Sam , help me !
[ Samantha ] Chris ! Grab my hand !
[ screaming ]
No !
[ screeching ]
- [ sizzles ] - [ screaming ]
[ continues screaming ]
[ screaming stops ]
[ roars , wails ]
[ sighs ]
You told us we 'd be safe !
You said the light would protect us !
Not true .
Mommy , Misty 's gone ! I can 't find her !
[ Anna ] Honey , not now .
You let her get me .
What are you talking about ?
You used my son as bait ?
No . Of course not .
I used all of you as bait .
Are you crazy ?
What if you didn 't get to him in time ?
But I did .
And now La Llorona is out of your house .
What are those ?
Remember the fire tree ?
Those are its seeds .
As long as this line remains unbroken ,
she cannot enter .
Do not touch them .
La Llorona will do whatever she can
to get back inside this house .
[ banging ]
- [ door slams open ] - [ Anna gasps ]
- [ Chris ] The back door ! - [ Anna ] Chris !
[ wind howling ]
Quick ! Grab a hammer and nails !
[ Chris ] She 's gonna get in !
[ grunting ]
Don 't let her in ! Don 't !
[ Rafael ] Away , spirit !
You have no power here !
Away from this family !
Anna , hurry !
[ wind chimes tinkling ]
[ Rafael ] Hold it steady ! Hold it !
Just a few more nails !
[ grunts ]
[ sighs ]
[ wind chimes tinkling ]
[ Anna ] Sam !
Get away from that door !
Mommy , I got Misty and I didn 't break the beans .
[ screaming ]
[ screams ]
[ grunting ]
Sam !
Sam ! Sam !
She 's gonna drown her .
Oh , God ! The pool !
Sam !
[ gasping ]
[ flashlight buzzing ]
[ screeching ]
Mom !
[ chanting in Spanish ]
- [ Anna screaming ] - [ screeching ]
Amen .
[ screaming stops ]
[ both gasp and cough ]
[ Anna ] Take her !
- Is she okay ? - She 's okay !
She 's breathing . She 's okay .
[ Anna panting ]
What did you do ?
Your pool is now filled with holy water .
La Llorona had no choice but to leave .
Thank you , honey .
Sweetie ?
Are you okay , honey ?
Sam . Sam .
Sam ?
What 's she doing ?
Sam .
What 's wrong with her ?
Rafael ?
La Llorona had your daughter in her grasp .
Now , when she calls to her she will go .
When we banish the spirit ,
her trance will be broken .
Until then , we have to keep them close .
[ Anna shivering ]
[ Anna ] What ? What are you thinking ?
What ? What do we do ?
Do we have to ?
[ Rafael ] Yes .
Just until sunrise .
Okay .
Okay , you gotta sit down . Sam .
Sweetie .
You are so brave .
Your daddy would be so proud of you .
The way you look after Sam and me .
I need you to know that it 's okay to be scared .
Everybody is , sometimes .
I am .
Daddy was .
Rafael ?
No .
He 's lying .
I love you , Mom .
I love you too , baby .
I love you both so much .
It 's okay , Mom . Do it .
[ wind whistling ]
Where did you get that ?
It 's hers .
[ Rafael ] Hers ?
[ Anna ] It was around her neck .
[ Rafael ] Keep it close .
We might be able to use it against her .
[ door creaking ]
[ Chris ] Mom ! Mom !
Chris !
- Chris ! - Mom !
Mom !
[ gun clicks ]
[ shrieks ]
[ Anna ] Patricia .
Patricia .
Patricia , please .
You took my babies from me !
- Don 't do this . - She 'll give them back to me .
[ Anna ] Patricia , please don 't do this !
Patricia , please .
Please put the gun down .
Okay ? We can talk about this .
You and I can just talk about this .
Okay ? Patricia , please .
[ groans ]
Please ...
Please bring them back to me .
No .
Give me back my boys !
[ thunder rumbles ]
No !
[ screaming ]
Mom !
Run ! [ chokes ]
[ grunting ]
[ thunder cracking ]
[ Samantha yelps ]
[ Chris ] Come on .
- It 's locked . - Mine too .
Let me check this one .
Chris , they 're all locked .
What do we do ?
[ groans ]
[ Samantha ] Hurry , Chris !
Please . Oh , God .
Come on ! She 's coming !
- She 's coming . She 's coming ! - I know !
- Faster ! - I got it !
Pull it !
[ Chris ] Go , go , go !
Come on . Hurry .
Grab the rope .
[ both grunting ]
She 's coming .
[ thunder rumbling ]
Help !
[ Chris ] Grab the light .
[ Samantha ] Here it is .
- [ screaming ] - [ Chris yells ]
[ both gasping ]
[ rope creaking ]
- No . - This way .
- [ Christmas carol playing ] - [ screams ]
- Follow me . - Okay , I 'm coming .
[ Chris ] No !
[ toy squeaks ]
[ song continues playing ]
- [ flashlight crackling ] - Oh , no .
- [ song slows down ] - No .
[ song stops ]
[ thunder cracking ]
[ breathing heavily ]
Get behind me .
Help !
They 're not your kids !
No !
Let them go !
[ muffled scraping ]
- [ loud thud ] - [ gasps ]
Go .
[ Anna ] Chris ! Sam !
[ gasps , groans ]
[ pounding on door ]
- [ screeching ] - [ children screaming ]
Kids !
Behold the cross of the Lord and begone , wicked spirit !
[ yells ]
[ Chris ] Mom !
[ Samantha ] Mom .
[ thunder cracking ]
Mis hijos !
[ Rafael ] Anna !
[ screeching ]
[ gasps ]
[ screams ]
[ La Llorona screeching ]
[ sizzles ]
[ groans ]
[ all gasping ]
[ Anna sobs ]
Ta-da !
[ Anna chuckles , cries ]
Come here .
It 's okay .
You 're okay now .
Thank you .
I don 't know how I could ever repay you .
[ chuckles softly ]
You two were very brave .
Even I was scared for a while .
Really ?
No .
Not really .
[ engine starts ]
Race you inside .
[ Chris and Samantha laughing ]
Subtitles by explosiveskull Sync by GoldenBeard
[ woman sobbing ]